UX/UI Designer - Product Designer

I specialize in designing user interfaces and digital products. The mix of design, user experience, marketing, branding, and business/domain knowledge is where I thrive.

Ownership of my decisions, pride in my work ethic, I don't shy away from hard work.

Throughout my career, I have taught myself to code in front-end languages, allowing me to put the vision I have for a product exactly as I've visualised it. I know the possibilities and restrictions of user interfaces and I know how to co-operate with teams.

Experience

Product Designer

Nera

Sept 2023 - Present

- Evolve Design System: Collaborate with the expansion and development of the existing design system, focusing on scalability, incorporating latest tools and methods.
- Craft Intuitive Interfaces: Design captivating and user-centric interfaces that enhance the overall product experience, considering user needs and business objectives.
- Cross-Functional Collaboration: Collaborate seamlessly with other UX designers, developers, and product owner to integrate design concepts that align with product goals.
- Drive Innovation: Keep abreast of industry trends, emerging technologies, and user behaviors to infuse innovative design solutions, contributing to the product's competitive edge and continuous improvement.
- -Prototype wireframes and flows to foster communication and understanding.

Lead Product Designer **Balloon Group**

May 2022 - Sept 2023

- Ensuring that the design work is of sufficient quality and that all directives are being followed.
- Developing and mantaining Design Systems for the company and it's clients.
- Collaborating with other departments to achieve Design
- Conducting and guiding Discovery workshops with clients.
- Working to meet the expectations of the customer.
- Delegating work and reviewing it as it advances and when it has been completed.
- Coordinating department meetings.

UI Designer - Contractor **Kinsu**

January 2023 - April 2023

Designed and improved the usability of an Insurance app. I developed a prototype for the company to present it's B2B business model to their stakeholders. I expanded their current UI Kit and styleguide.

UI Designer - Contractor

PPL Events

December 2022 - Present

Designed the interface for a web app, expanding existing design systems, and working in design sprints with a team in USA.

Branding - Freelance Various Clients

Sep 2018 - Present

Website redesign, including building and handling the e-commerce - Ecoaqua - www.ecoaqua.com.ar

Designing the brand identity, logo and brand book. Landing and e-commerce design and deployment (Wordpress, WooComerce)

Branding & Web Redesign - Oriens Energía - www.oriens.com.ar

Wordpress. New logo and brand identity, brand book, Digital MKT training for the board directors.

E-mail Marketing Business Analyst

Dos Monos

Dec 2016 - Aug 2017

Data driven analysis, segmentation and optimization, improving conversion rates, clicks, and increasing all around revenue for the company. -Testing and experimentation. A/B Testing

Education

The Interaction Design Foundation

UX/UI Design, Research and Management

Dec 2022 - Present

Languages

Spanish - Native English - Professional

University of Buenos Aires (UBA - FADU)

Industrial Design

Aug 2017 – Jun 2021

Skills

Product discovery
Business analysis
UX research
User testing
Customer journey mapping
Information architecture
Wireframing
Prototyping

UI design
Illustration
Interaction design
Design system
Design sprints
A/B testing
Agile Methodologies

Figma
Adobe Illustrator
Miro
Notion
Jira
HTML
CSS

ReactJs